<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>foi on rOpenGov - R packages for open government data analytics</title>
    <link>/tags/foi/</link>
    <description>Recent content in foi on rOpenGov - R packages for open government data analytics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/foi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cost of academic publishing in Finland</title>
      <link>/2018/12/cost-of-academic-publishing-in-finland/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/12/cost-of-academic-publishing-in-finland/</guid>
      <description>Cost of academic publishing in Finland 2010-2017 Subscription costs to scientific publishers in Finland 2010-2017 This post provides a brief overview of the subscription prices paid by Finnish research institutions to academic publishers in 2010-2017.
Finland is possibly the only country that has systematically released subscription prices that research libraries pay to academic publishers as open data. The data is available for all major research institutions in Finland.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scientific journal subscription costs in Finland 2010-2015</title>
      <link>/2016/06/scientific-journal-subscription-costs-in-finland-2010-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/06/scientific-journal-subscription-costs-in-finland-2010-2015/</guid>
      <description>Scientific journal subscription costs in Finland: a preliminary analysis Detailed information on journal subscription costs paid to individual publishers by the Finnish research institutions has been released by the Finnish Ministry of Education and Culture, and its Open Science and Research Initiative funded 2014–2017 (Academic Publishing Costs in Finland 2010–2015).
With this, Finland becomes to our knowledge the first country where annual subscription fees for all individual publishers and all major research institutions have been made available, spanning the years 2010-2015.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
