<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on rOpenGov - R packages for open government data analytics</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on rOpenGov - R packages for open government data analytics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hetu-package for handling of Finnish personal identity codes</title>
      <link>/2020/10/hetu-package-for-handling-of-finnish-personal-identity-codes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/10/hetu-package-for-handling-of-finnish-personal-identity-codes/</guid>
      <description>pre  code.sourceCode { white-space: pre; position: relative; } pre  code.sourceCode  span { display: inline-block; line-height: 1.25; } pre  code.sourceCode  span:empty { height: 1.2em; } code.sourceCode  span { color: inherit; text-decoration: inherit; } div.sourceCode { margin: 1em 0; } pre.sourceCode { margin: 0; } @media screen { div.sourceCode { overflow: auto; } } @media print { pre  code.sourceCode { white-space: pre-wrap; } pre  code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello rOpenGov</title>
      <link>/2020/10/hello-ropengov/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2020 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/10/hello-ropengov/</guid>
      <description>R Markdown This is an R Markdown document. Markdown is a simple formatting syntax for authoring HTML, PDF, and MS Word documents. For more details on using R Markdown see http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com.
You can embed an R code chunk like this:
summary(cars) ## speed dist ## Min. : 4.0 Min. : 2.00 ## 1st Qu.:12.0 1st Qu.: 26.00 ## Median :15.0 Median : 36.00 ## Mean :15.4 Mean : 42.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cost of academic publishing in Finland</title>
      <link>/2018/12/cost-of-academic-publishing-in-finland/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/12/cost-of-academic-publishing-in-finland/</guid>
      <description>Cost of academic publishing in Finland 2010-2017 Subscription costs to scientific publishers in Finland 2010-2017 This post provides a brief overview of the subscription prices paid by Finnish research institutions to academic publishers in 2010-2017.
Finland is possibly the only country that has systematically released subscription prices that research libraries pay to academic publishers as open data. The data is available for all major research institutions in Finland.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presenting at useR2017 in Brussels</title>
      <link>/2017/07/presenting-at-user2017-in-brussels/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/07/presenting-at-user2017-in-brussels/</guid>
      <description>Annual useR-conference is organised this year in Brussels, Belgium. rOpenGov will be presenting in two occasion on Thursday 6th. Leo Lahti will give an general overview of rOpenGov in his lightning talk rOpenGov - Community project for open government data at 17.50 in room 3.02. At 13.30 in Plenary room Markus Kainu will speak about Community-based learning and knowledge sharing - Teaching R withing organisation using edu -package.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>eurostat package published in R Journal</title>
      <link>/2017/04/eurostat-package-published-in-r-journal/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/04/eurostat-package-published-in-r-journal/</guid>
      <description>   eurostat package published in R Journal A formal publication on the eurostat CRAN R package has now appeared on-line in R Journal.
Further details on installation and use are provided at the package homepage, tutorial and cheat sheet. Blog posts provide further and more advanced examples on the package use.
We are also collecting information about publications using the eurostat R package, suggestions are welcome.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scientific journal subscription costs in Finland 2010-2015</title>
      <link>/2016/06/scientific-journal-subscription-costs-in-finland-2010-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2016/06/scientific-journal-subscription-costs-in-finland-2010-2015/</guid>
      <description>Scientific journal subscription costs in Finland: a preliminary analysis Detailed information on journal subscription costs paid to individual publishers by the Finnish research institutions has been released by the Finnish Ministry of Education and Culture, and its Open Science and Research Initiative funded 2014–2017 (Academic Publishing Costs in Finland 2010–2015).
With this, Finland becomes to our knowledge the first country where annual subscription fees for all individual publishers and all major research institutions have been made available, spanning the years 2010-2015.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R made personal (at least for swedes)!</title>
      <link>/2015/08/r-made-personal-at-least-for-swedes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/08/r-made-personal-at-least-for-swedes/</guid>
      <description>R made personal (at least for swedes)! Background – Who are you? asked Mr Doe.
– I’m a Hindu! Namrata from India replied.
– I’m a statistician! said Günther from Germany.
People of different nationalities tend to identify themselves using different characteristics. In India, your identity might rely on your religion, while in other countries your profession might take its place. In Sweden, you might identify yourself with your almost-world-known (!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital humanities with R</title>
      <link>/2015/06/digital-humanities-with-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/06/digital-humanities-with-r/</guid>
      <description>Digital humanities is one of the fields where reproducible research is now becoming increasingly popular. We got an opportunity to highlight the latest advancement in this field in Paris Digital Humanities event, June 12 at Deutsches Historische Institut Paris.
The ‘digital humanities lab’ is an interactive experiment where the audience actively participates in designing the analysis of massive library catalogues. In particular, we focused on publishing activity in the early modern period by mining the British Library ESTC catalogue 1470-1800.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A hierarchical model of Finnish apartment prices</title>
      <link>/2015/06/a-hierarchical-model-of-finnish-apartment-prices/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/06/a-hierarchical-model-of-finnish-apartment-prices/</guid>
      <description>Probabilistic programming approach for regional trends in apartment prices Basing on open data from Statistics Finland, we at Reaktor modelled Finnish apartment prices and their trends on zip-code level, in the years 2005–2014. Estimates from the model are available as an interactive visualization.
Why do (statistical) modeling? The original price data consists of local (geometric) mean sales prices per year. The number of sales is available as well. If there are less than six sales, the mean price is censored.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reproducible posters with R, LaTeX, tikz and Sweave</title>
      <link>/2015/06/reproducible-posters-with-r-latex-tikz-and-sweave/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/06/reproducible-posters-with-r-latex-tikz-and-sweave/</guid>
      <description>rOpenGov is all about reproducible research, so preparing a reproducible poster became our mission after having the chance to present at International Conference on Computational Social Science (ICCSS 2015) in Helsinki, June 8-11, 2015 (poster 36 in Monday session 15:30-17:00).
We blended R code and output with the standard poster contents. The poster sources download data with our eurostat R package and automatically generates the final figures and the overall layout.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finnish Meteorological Institute open data added to rOpenGov</title>
      <link>/2014/09/finnish-meteorological-institute-open-data-added-to-ropengov/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/09/finnish-meteorological-institute-open-data-added-to-ropengov/</guid>
      <description>FMI package for Finnish Meteorological Institute An R package fmi for the Finnish Meteorological Institute open data API has been released. The package provides an access from R to many data sets including weather conditions, climate scenarios, sea related observations and sun radiation in Finland. Installation instructions, examples and other details are provided in the tutorial. The package is in beta and test experiences and contributions are welcome! For the contact details, see the package home page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Berlin Open Knowledge Festival</title>
      <link>/2014/07/berlin-open-knowledge-festival/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/07/berlin-open-knowledge-festival/</guid>
      <description>Open Knowledge Festival - Berlin, July 15-17, 2014 rOpenGov developers met at the Open Knowledge Festival in Berlin, July 15-17. We discussed the development of representation formats for social/political science data sets. The psData package for panel series data is now under active development, and further plans include similar structures for election and other data sources. Standardized representation formats will allow the development and application of analysis algorithms beyond particular applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NIPS/MLOSS workshop on Machine Learning Open Source Software</title>
      <link>/2013/12/nips/mloss-workshop-on-machine-learning-open-source-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/12/nips/mloss-workshop-on-machine-learning-open-source-software/</guid>
      <description>NIPS/MLOSS workshop on Machine Learning Open Source Software The rOpenGov project was today highlighted at the Neural Information Processing Systems (NIPS) conference, one of the main forums for machine learning and scientific computation. We gave a presentation at the Machine Learning Open Source Software (MLOSS) workshop.
A number of other interesting projects were present, including iPython, Factorie, scikit-learn, and many others. For a full list, see the MLOSS site.
While the rOpenGov ecosystem is based on R, we actively seek connections with related initiatives in other languages, such as Python or Julia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R Ecosystem for Open Government Data and Computational Social Science</title>
      <link>/2013/12/r-ecosystem-for-open-government-data-and-computational-social-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/12/r-ecosystem-for-open-government-data-and-computational-social-science/</guid>
      <description>Hello world !
This is to announce the rOpenGov project and encourage new contributions to promote community-driven development of R tools for open government data and computational social science.
A community of independent package developers around open goverment data analytics is now emerging at rOpenGov. Independent projects dedicated to US, Russia, Finland, Poland, Austria, and OpenStreetMap have already joined in; more are coming and we will keep you posted through this blog.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
